

# **SHIVANI BRIJMOHAN**

# **Frontend Engineer**

Frontend Engineer with a passion for quality. I have an eagle eye for detail and digital storytelling. I'm a firm believer that it's important for everyone to have the ability to unleash their freedom of expression and come together to challenge convention and create positive change.

## **SKILLS**

<HTML>

<CSS>

<Javascript>

<Ruby on Rails>

<SCSS>

<React>

<Semantic UI>

<GIT>

<Bootstrap> <AWS>

<Heroku>

<Firebase>

<GraphOL>

<SOL>

<TDD>

<REST>

<Redux>

<Agile>

<Scrum>

## CONTACT

shivani.brijmohan@gmail.com (352)573-9399 **PORTFOLIO** 

## **AWARDS**

**Bose AR & Company Pitch Contest Challenge Winner** for Shleepy. A public transit GPS alarm navigation app for iPhone and Bose augmented reality devices.

The StartupBus & JP Morgan, Advancing Black **Entrepreneurs** where I created & launched a startup on a bus from NYC to NOLA in 72 hours.

Second Place Winner at Access Labs **Hackathon** creating access to health care for all.

## TECHNICAL PROJECTS

**SHLEEPY** Currently in development Bose AR and The Company Challenge Grand Prize Winner against 10

As a cofounder I do everything from create traction for my application, develop a wireframe, and application prototype. Shleepy helps New Yorkers avoid delays, and other subway transit disruptions with real-time updates. Built with Swift programming language and integrated with Bose Augmented Reality SDK to connect devices and provide a sensor-driven audio experience. Employs Google Maps SDK for turn by turn directions. SKILLS: SWIFT, BOSE AR SDK, GOOGLE MAPS SDK

#### **DUMBOVIEW**

#### **DUMBOVIEW**

A Shopify e-commerce retail website where visitors can purchase DUMBOVIEWS branded merchandise. Built using Shopify dev tools. Implemented client's InVision design specs. Added products and set up inventory. Created product and site SEO keywords and set up Google Ads and Facebook Ads.

SKILLS: SHOPIFY, INVISION

#### BOUNCE

**GITHUB** 

**DEMONSTRATION** 

Bounce is a music streaming application that allows a user to browse and save playlists. Built with a Ruby on Rails backend to authorize user. Built frontend using React to responsively update components. Bounce fetches data from the Napster API. Custom styling with CSS and integrated Semantic UI. SKILLS: JAVASCRIPT, RUBY ON RAILS, CSS, REACT, NAPSTER API, **SEMANTIC UI** 

**BOOM** WEBSITE **GITHUB** 

**DEMONSTRATION** 

A Javascript toy where a user can press any letter a-z and create an animation and sound that correlates with that letter. Built with a Ruby on Rails backend to save users clips. Two libraries were used for the frontend Howler JS for the sound clips and Paper JS for the animations. SKILLS: JAVASCRIPT, RUBY ON RAILS, HOWLER JS, PAPER JS

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## FREELANCE DEVELOPER, May 2017-present

- · Developing and optimizing website static websites from scratch using HTML, CSS, and Javascript.
- Integrated JSON and REST, RESTFul API'S with JavaScript Frameworks(React)
- · Collaborating with production managers, marketing, and support teams to launch products on time and within budget.

## THE STARTUP BUS (STOCKAID) August 2019 STOCKAID GITHUB Frontend Engineer

- Created and deployed (in 72 hours) a fullstack CRUD educational stock application for students from the ages of 13-18.
- · Application used React, Firebase, CSS, Semantic UI
- · Practiced Agile Methodoligies, Designed, and created wireframe,

## Center for Visual Communications, December 2017- May 2018 **Production Manager**

- Managed exhibit preparation and maintenance during Art Basel Miami 2017.
- · Lead the Hurricane Project, a project by Barry Fellman Commemorating the 25th Anniversary of Hurricane Andrew through successful delivery.
- · Managed teams driving them to meet deliverables by team meetings, staff performance reviews and reward are good signals of strong leadership in project management.

## **EDUCATION**

## FLATIRON'S ACCESS LABS / SOFTWARE ENGINEERING IMMERSIVE **PROGRAM**

January 2019 - April 2019

## FLORIDA INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY / B.A LIBERAL ARTS August 2010 - August 2015